[snorts]
>> Surreal to be at the last week of the
season?
Um, just focus on the game, you know,
just doing everything we can to find a
way to win.
Is it
challenging at all to
make sure everyone's locked in on that
and not thinking about
>> found that at all. Uh, it's been great
energy from our guys. Um,
helpful that we've won the last two.
You know, I think to keep the energy up
at this point of year, but but
everybody's been great. Do you think
there's value in in winning these games
to show
the front office, "Hey, this offseason
if we make a couple of moves, we can be
right back where we were
>> showing anybody. I mean, we're all in
this thing together, so I don't think
there's any need to show anybody
anything.
Zack talked to you a couple weeks ago
about how you evaluate all quarterbacks
in the draft.
When you guys have looked at Shedeur
Sanders, what stood out to you as
something that, you know, impressed you
about him and from what you've seen on
film getting ready for this Sunday? I I
think he elevated a program, you know,
he he certainly, um, helped bring a lot
of eyes to Colorado because they did
some great things when he was there and
um,
you know, I I'm never going to call
myself a Colorado fan and I was watching
their games, you know, as a Nebraska
guy, so,
um, you know, I I thought that he did a
great job, you know, in
uh, collaboration with a lot of other
people that that really did a great job
at Colorado.
Um,
and so then for him to come in the
league and as a rookie have success, I
think it's really impressive. And so
again, we've got a tough task in front
of us and he's done a real good job and
he's got confidence. He's he's obviously
got a lot of reps under his belt now and
um, he's made a lot of plays for these
guys. I know there's only so much you
you were kind of looking at guys, you
know, in day three. Was there any
surprise like in that room when a guy
like Shedeur fell as far as he did it
especially to a division rival knowing
that you're probably going to face him
at some point?
I mean, I don't know if I have a good
response to that.
How do you view Fairbairn and Demetrius
entering 2026 now 10-15 starts into
their individual careers? Yeah, um, just
finish this season strong, you know, and
just keep making progress like they have
been over the course of the season. So,
that's really the the focus right now is
um,
one more good day, great work today and
then and then we'll focus on tomorrow
and and make sure that we just finish
the season the right way and then next
next spring we'll evaluate all that
stuff that needs to be evaluated.
Quietly, special teams has been one of
the top ranked in the Yeah. What what uh
what has caught your eye
about them?
What I've really, you know,
I agree with that all season. I've
really felt that the last couple weeks
especially.
Um, that's been really strong just on
kickoff coverage.
In general, you're you're seeing every
team in the league right now is there
there's a kickoff that's getting to the
40 occasionally. That's just the way
it's going right now, but um, I feel
like they've done a really good job
limiting the field position. I think
the, you know, punting we've gotten
several punts now down inside the five
over the last couple weeks.
Our coverage units have been really
strong. We've gotten good returns.
Um, obviously Darrin and Ben are doing
an outstanding job of getting everybody
organized and our guys are totally
bought in.
And it's it's given us some advantage. I
really feel like we've had advantage in
special teams and that's a credit to to
Darrin and Ben and everybody that's been
a part of that unit. So, you guys have
survived some injuries to, you know,
Shakur, PJ, guys who were,
you know,
key guys. You guys have kind of survived
that. Yeah, and I think we've had, you
know,
guys that may have been on the practice
squad for us that have stepped up as
well and and again, I I really think
Darrin does a great job of getting
everybody ready because he's he's been a
part of this a long time and he knows
how it works especially as you get later
in the year and you're going to have to
utilize different people. And so he's
he's done a good job putting them in the
right spot and getting the most out of
them. When you're going when you're when
you know you're going to take growing
pains and you're going to you're going
to building towards something, at the
end of the season, what are you hoping
that looks like?
That process, what does that process
look like at the end of the season? What
are you hoping that that looks like?
That it's helping us win games. That's
the biggest thing for me. When you're
looking at assessing the growth of some
of those guys through those growing
pains, what are you hoping you see from
them at the end of the year versus when
they were, you know, put in in in their
roles early? That they just made
continued improvement throughout every
single week. Do you feel like you've
seen that a lot from the young guys that
you've played this year? Absolutely.
Yep. Over the last two weeks, you've
gotten a chance to look at your second
team, for lack of a better word. Um,
what do you thought? What was your
evaluation of kind of the those units?
Well, it uh, it can be tough
tough circumstances
because often times the offense goes out
there, we're we're trying to run the
ball.
Um, and so we're trying to get first
downs without throwing it and and that
can be a challenge because they know
you're doing that. So, uh, their backs
are against the wall a little bit. So,
it can be a tough evaluation. You're
you're evaluating the technique and and
our targeting and
all that kind of stuff. Defensively,
obviously the ball's in the air a lot,
you know, so we're having to defend a
lot of plays, typically on the ball
two-minute stuff that they haven't
really worked since training camp. So,
we want stops, you know, we don't want
to give up the late fourth quarter
touchdowns like we have the last two
weeks, so we still have a high standard
there. Offensively, we still want to put
points on the board. Um, all the while
though, you're getting an opportunity
just to see guys go out there and
compete and communicate and utilize the
technique that that's being taught to
them and the communication skills and
um, and and we want to not allow points
and create a turnover and and go get
some points on the board on offense as
well. How do you evaluate Joe Flacco's
running dive?
Uh, it was good, you know, he did
everything he needed to do to get done
to to get the job done and that's that's
all we needed on that play is get the
first down and keep the sticks moving
and and so, um,
as a fellow 40s year old man, it's
impressive, you know, I I
I can't do that. With the calendar year
coming to a close, what's your New
Year's resolution?
To beat Cleveland.
Key Shawn Williams has been here for two
weeks. He's had a big return in each
game. He got a game ball last week. Has
he done enough in a couple of weeks to
be a guy that you want to, you know, try
to develop going forward? Well, I think
he's he's great in the role that he's
been for us this season.
Um, especially with Charlie being out
these last couple weeks and and so
again, he's got great energy to him like
Kevin O'Morrall. He's picked things up
pretty quickly.
Um,
you know, the jet sweep I called to him
in in the Miami game was spur of the
moment. Let's give it to to Key Shawn
and
um, wasn't until after the play I
realized he might not know the word that
we were saying in the huddle to give him
the ball. And so I I'd love to hear a
mic'd up dialogue between him and Flacco
of that communication, but I I think
he'd done an excellent job speaks to him
of studying the playbook and had seen it
and
got himself aware of it and Troy or
whoever had helped him and um, so he's
picked it up pretty quickly and and it's
been fun to watch him make some plays.
We'll see. [clears throat] I think I
think with him and Isaiah we'll keep
letting, you know, tomorrow and Friday
play out and see where he ends up.
Given what
given what the offense has gone through
this year with three quarterbacks,
uh,
what kind of year would you say Jamar
had
last year but even though I mean, he
doesn't have the numbers, but
given what he went through this year,
how would you
Yeah, I mean, yeah, I would I would, um,
I would say he's got the numbers, you
know, he's he's just shy of last year in
terms of the catches and missed a game.
I don't think last year he missed any
games.
Uh, so, you know, I I think he's
he is, uh,
kind of like we talk about with Myles
Garrett this week. I I know other teams
are talking about Jamar Chase, you know,
and
the Bengals are going to get him the
ball. We have to not allow him to get
the ball.
He still finds ways to get the ball. Um,
still finds ways to make plays even when
he's got a lot of attention on him. So,
um, I I think he's had an outstanding
season and, you know, to have the
production that he's had,
um, that we've always been able to rely
on and and he's a hard piece to take
away, you know, and and he's that's
credit to him because I've said this
before, but
you can utilize him in a million
different ways because he's capable of
understanding it all and it makes sense
to him and and he studies.
And if he if he didn't do that, then
he'd be a lot more one-dimensional one
spot, you know, you put him in one spot,
leave him in one spot, but because he
can do it all, it allows you to to move
him around and get him touches. Speaking
of Myles, you know, I'm sure you watched
the Pittsburgh film and what the
Steelers did. It felt like they really
tried to take away Myles almost to an
extent to where it kind of hurt their
offense. How do you weigh that kind of
balance?
>> Yeah, I I I don't agree with that. I
think every team every team goes in
there with Myles Garrett on every single
play, "What are we going to do to limit
him?" And so I think, um, you know, I've
heard that a couple times about
Pittsburgh just trying to win the game
and and the way to do that is you have
to limit Myles Garrett's effectiveness.
And you watch every other tape that's
been on all season, teams are doing
everything they can to limit his
effectiveness. Every run, every pass,
every screen, every naked, um, it all
has 95 in mind. And and our plan has
never been any differently.
Um, you want to limit his effectiveness
and and uh, he makes as much of an
impact on a game as any player in the
NFL. Period. And
um, so again, it's you think about 95 in
your head every second of every week
you're playing the Cleveland Browns. He
is he is
you're you're going to be ready for him.
Is that why they're such a tough matchup
for you guys stylistically because
>> They're a tough matchup for every team
they've ever played. And and so again,
it's sure it it always
feels ugly when you play them because
he's disruptive, their whole front's
disruptive, their backers are fast and
confident. Um, they have outstanding
cover corners, you know, Denzel,
um, does a tremendous job as well as
everybody else. And so they they they
play to their scheme. They don't they're
not overly complicated, which is which
is a positive for them. They they
they play to their guys' strengths and
they do an outstanding job and Schwartz
does a great job of countering when he
needs to and um, so it's a challenge not
just for us, but for for every team
we've ever seen on tape against them and
um, you got to be really smart when you
play against them. How big would it be
for the offense to have another big
week? You guys have back-to-back huge
weeks, really productive. To to do it
against a a defense that you know is
challenging.
>> Yeah, I I I focus it's just I want a W
on the scoreboard when this game's over.
You know, I think it says Bengals win
sometimes in the Jumbotron. I've gotten
a picture with my family before out
there and so I I want that after the
game, you know, and that's that's the
only focus for me. I know winning's
obviously a primary focus, but how much
is, you know, Sunday is an opportunity
against against Miles and the defensive
line a chance for you guys to kind of
see how far this offensive line has
grown that, you know, from week one to
now because certainly it's gotten better
as the season has gone on. I I just I
wanted to see this finish finish on the
note that we've we've had at the end of
the season here and so um again, I've
got a lot of confidence in the offensive
line. They're they're up for the task
whether it's against the Browns
defensive line or anybody. I've seen
that from them. So I know what I'm going
to get.
And and I've got a ton of respect for
all the guys that are that line up in
front of Joe and protect for him and
block for him and um so I'm just again
excited to watch these guys finish on a
strong note. Once you get through once
you get through Sunday or Monday, at
what point do you start evaluating the
season as a whole and start going
through and saying, you know, look at
what we did right and what we did wrong.
What How does that What does that
process look like?
>> Well, I think that's a weekly process
really for us as the season goes. We
reflect on so you're not just at the end
of the season, oh, let's let's look back
at all 18 weeks. You know, that's we we
got a good sense of that. So um
you know, we we'll have our rapid
meetings early next week with with
players, with coaches, with everybody in
the building. Um and then you move on to
the next phase of the off-season and so
that's really no different than what has
been in the past and and I always look
forward to that process. It's it's a
it's a change. You've You've been
scheming all season and studying tape
and and then you get to go on to the
next phase and um
you know, take a breath at some point,
but but there's still a lot of work to
do and I'm excited about it.
>> You know, I think that being said, when
you go back and look at the middle of
the season, if there's one thing you
wish you would have had back, you know,
given how you finished, what would you
have liked besides having Joe being
healthy more than anything? Yeah, just
there was a lot of games where in any
phase we just needed to make one more
play and we didn't do it. So that's
that's closing out games. That could
have been a call. That could have been a
lot of things and
um you know, but but right now
again, those are things that we'll go
back and watch all these games again in
the off-season, but right now it's just
focused on let's let's find a way to
beat these guys cuz it's going to be a
tough game. You obviously made some
coaching changes last year at this time
right after week 18. How do you think
the coaching staff overall your
evaluation of them? I know you have one
more game left. Just
Real excited. Really excited about the
direction these guys are going.
You know, um a lot of the new guys were
on defense, O-line guys. Uh really
pleased with how they've just fit as a
staff. The the type of people they are,
the type of workers they are, their
football IQ, their ability to work well
with others and
adapt a scheme and
have great ideas and I think that we've
got really a a really strong collection
of coaches that
um I always feel this way that over the
next 10 years you're going to see
unbelievable things from everybody on
the staff and um I see them every day
and know what they're capable of and um
don't ever want to lose any of them cuz
I think that we have a really really
really strong coaching staff.
Thank you. Thanks Zac. Thanks Zac.